A Guide to the William Ingham Papers, 1945-2013: SC 0002
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
- Series 4: JMU Departmental and JMU Materials, 1976-2012
  - 4.1: JMU Materials, 1976-2012
    - Interdisciplinary Science Project, 1993-1994 (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - JMUniverse, 1998 (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - JMU/CSM Commencement Address, 2010 (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - JMU Emeriti Association Newsletters, 2011-2012 (Box 71, Folder 13)
    - JMU Recycling, undated (Box 71, Folder 14)
    - Information Literacy for Teaching and Learning: A Workshop for Faculty and Librarians, 2006 (Box 71, Folder 15)
    - Information Literacy for Teaching and Learning: A Workshop for Faculty and Librarians, 2008 (Box 71, Folder 16)
    - JMU/NEH Faculty Development Workshop for Teachers of the Freshman Seminar, 1990 (Box 71, Folder 17)
    - JMU/NEH Faculty Workshop, 1989 (Box 71, Folder 18)
    - Joint Meeting of the Faculty and Staff: The Centennial Year, 2007 (Box 71, Folder 19)
    - "Living in Exile" Conference, 2002 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Madison Magazine and Commencement Program, 2009-2010 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Montpelier Magazine, 1998 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Montpelier Magazine, 2001 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - On-Campus Correspondence, 1976-1985 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Report of Committee on Programs for Outstanding Students, 1986 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Linwood Rose/ Jonathan Alger Transition, 2011-2012 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - SCHEV/Madison Conference, 1992 (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Undergraduate Research Symposium, 2007 (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - University Organizational Chart, 1998 (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Workshops, 2006-2008 (Box 72, Folder 11)
  - 4.2: Physics Department Materials, 1976-2011
    - AAAS/Kistiakowsky Visiting Scholar Program/Edward Warner, 1987 (Box 72, Folder 12)
    - AAAS/VQUEST Correspondence, 1993 (Box 72, Folder 13)
    - AAPT/PTRA Applications (Folder 1 of 2), 2002-2005 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - AAPT/PTRA Applications (Folder 2 of 2), 2002-2005 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Action needed file, 1998 (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Activities & Accomplishments, 1977-1989 (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Activities & Accomplishments, 1993-1998 (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Activities & Accomplishments, 1999-2003 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Activities & Accomplishments, 2003-2004 (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Activities & Accomplishments, 2004-2006 (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Activities & Accomplishments, 2006-2007 (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Activities & Accomplishments, 2008 (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Activities & Accomplishments, 2008-2009 (Box 73, Folder 11)
    - Advising Notes, 1987-1994 (Box 73, Folder 12)
    - AEL Financial Records, 1993-1995 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - AEL Grant Proposal for ISTEE, Early Drafts, 1993 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - AEL Grant Proposal for ISTEE, 1993 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - AEL Grant Proposal for ISTEE, 1993 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - AEL Notes/Backfile, 1994-1995 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Alumni Records, 1990-2007 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - "An Appreciation of Hans Bethe," Physics Seminar, 2005 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Annual Faculty Evaluations, 1977-1994 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - AP Summer Institutes, 2008-2009 (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Arts & Sciences Symposium, 1979 (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - Beowulf, 1998-1999 (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - Blank Calendars and Schedules, undated (Box 74, Folder 12)
    - Blank Month Charts, undated (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - The Breeze, Vol. 73, No. 6, 1995 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - The Breeze, Vol. 76, No. 18, 1998 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Budget: Working Notes, 1993-1996 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Calendar Sheets, 2006-2007 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Calendar Sheets, 2008-2009 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Calendars, 2007-2008 (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Calendars & Flyer, 1999-2003 (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - CG APP/PTRA, 2002-2003 (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - CG APP/PTRA Stuff, 2003-2005 (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - College of Science and Mathematics Honors, 1996 (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - College of Science & Math Educational Leave Proposal, 2004 (Box 75, Folder 12)
    - College of Science & Mathematics Honors Night, 2010 (Box 75, Folder 13)
    - Comet Halley Talks, 1985-1986 (Box 75, Folder 14)
    - Computational Sciences Project Overview, 1998 (Box 75, Folder 15)
    - Computational Sciences Proposal, 1997-1998 (Box 75, Folder 16)
    - Computer Notes, 1999-2000 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Computer Purchase, 1993-1995 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Course Evaluations, 1981-1989 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Course Evaluations, 1982 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Current Workfile, 1999 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Daily Calendar/Planner, 1990 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Department Head Evaluations, 2001 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Dingledine Scholarship, 2006 (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Distinguished Teacher Award, 2002 (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - Diversified Studies in Physics Proposal, 1995-2000 (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - Educational Leave, Dan Larson Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 76, Folder 11)
    - Elementary Education Summer Workshop, 1986 (Box 76, Folder 12)
    - Energy Sources Seminar, 1983 (Box 76, Folder 13)
    - Evaluations of Others, 1977-1993 (Box 76, Folder 14)
    - Elementary School Presentation, 1978 (Box 76, Folder 15)
    - Feynman Lectures 1986, 1981-1986 (Box 76, Folder 16)
    - Bob Gordon 50-Year Reception, 2009-2010 (Box 76, Folder 17)
    - Jim Gumnick Visit: ORAU/ORNL, 1987-1989 (Box 76, Folder 18)
    - Facilities Access Request, 2007 (Box 76, Folder 19)
    - Faculty Activity Records, 1976-1988 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Faculty Summer Research Grant, 1977-1978 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Faculty Summer Research Grant, 1985 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Faculty Summer Research Grant, 1985-1986 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Faculty Summer Research Grant, 1992-1993 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Freshman Seminar Curriculum Guides, 1992 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Freshman Seminar Lecture: Philip Morrison, 1988-1991 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Future of PTRA, 2005 (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - Hangin' with Isaac and Henri, 2008, undated (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - HIST 339: The Life and Times of James Madison; Inventing America Symposium, 2006-2007 (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Honors 300, "Life Beyond Earth" Brown Bag Lunch Talk, 1997 (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - Individual Development Plans, 1995-1998 (Box 77, Folder 12)
    - STEE: The Behavior of Pendulums (Wed 7/13. 2:45-4pm), 1994 (Box 77, Folder 13)
    - ISTEE: Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 77, Folder 14)
    - ISTEE Course Content, 1994 (Box 77, Folder 15)
    - ISTEE Evaluations, 1993-1994 (Box 77, Folder 16)
    - ISTEE, Handouts for Workshop, 1994 (Box 77, Folder 17)
    - ISTEE: Heat, Work, & All That (Thurs 7/21, 9-10:15PM), 1994 (Box 77, Folder 18)
    - ISTEE July Workshop, 1994 (Box 77, Folder 19)
    - ISTEE, Materials Submitted by teachers, 1993-1994 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - ISTEE: Physics, Chemistry & the Summer Sky (Thurs 7/14, 10:30-12 noon), 1994 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - ISTEE Purchasing File, 1994-1995 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - ISTEE Report, 1994 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - ISTEE Teacher-Consultant Journals, 1994 (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - ISTEE: Teachers, 1993-1994 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - ISTEE Teacher-Consultants Meeting, 1994 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - ISTEE: Vibrations & Waves 9Thurs 7/14, 1:00-2:30pm), 1994 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - William Lanouette Visit, 1996 (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - James J. Leary & William Ingham, An Intuitive Derivation, undated (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - Lifelong Learning Institute: Einstein, 2006 (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - Lifelong Learning Institute, "Einstein Lived Here", 2006-2011 (Box 78, Folder 12)
    - Cheryl Linhart-Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 78, Folder 13)
    - Math/Science Education, 1987-1989 (Box 78, Folder 14)
    - Greg Meeks Lecture, 2001 (Box 78, Folder 15)
    - Lynn Miller, 2001 (Box 78, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 2008 (Box 78, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous Physics Department Material, 1997-1995 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Physics Department Material, 1992-2006 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Physics Department Material, 2005-2011 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Phil & Phyllis Morrison, 1978-1992 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Philip Morrison Biography, 1987-2005 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Phillip Morrison Visit, 1978-1989 (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - "Music in Context", 1984-1985 (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Newsprint items, 1976-1990 (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - Notes for Workshop, 1993-1994 (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - On-Campus Correspondence, 1978-1989 (Box 79, Folder 10)
    - On-Campus Correspondence, 1988-2010 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - PAC Work, 2009 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Personal Correspondence, 2000-2010 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Physics Alumni Lecture, Keith Brill, 2006 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Physics Department, 2000-2001 (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Physics Department, 2005-2008 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Physics Department Academic Program Review, 2008 (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Physics Department Address Book, 2008 (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Physics Department Annual Report, 1985-1988 (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Physics Department Class Schedule, Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1982-2004 (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - Physics Department Development and Annual Report, 1996-2003 (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - Physics Department General Materials, 1983 (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - Physics Department Meeting Minutes, 2009 (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Physics Department PAC Evaluations, 1997-2007 (Box 80, Folder 14)
    - Physics Department Retreat, 1995-1998 (Box 80, Folder 15)
    - Physics Department Retreat, 2008 (Box 80, Folder 16)
    - Physics Department Strategic Plan, 1997-1998 (Box 80, Folder 17)
    - Physics Film Series, 1986 (Box 80, Folder 18)
    - Physics Information Literacy, 2010 (Box 80, Folder 19)
    - Physics is Fun, 1979-1984 (Box 80, Folder 20)
    - Physics Textbooks, 1990-2007 (Box 80, Folder 21)
    - Plagiarism Resource Site, 2005 (Box 80, Folder 22)
    - Professional Goals, 1976-1992 (Box 80, Folder 23)
    - Promotion & Tenure, 1981 (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Promotion & Tenure, Attachment 1, 1981 (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Promotion & Tenure, Attachment 2,3,6,7, 1981 (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Promotion & Tenure, 1989 (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - PTRA, 2003-2005 (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - PTRA, 2005 (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - PTRA Binder, 2003-2005 (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - PTRA Fall Workshop, 2002-2003 (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - PTRA Fall Workshop, 2003-2004 (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - PTRA Letters, 2003 (Box 81, Folder 10)
    - PTRA Letters, 2004-2005 (Box 81, Folder 11)
    - PTRA, Physics 501, 2002-2003 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - PTRA Summer Institute, 2002 (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - PTRA Summer Institute, 2003 (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - PTRA Summer Institute, 2004 (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - PTRA Photos, 2004 (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - Public Understanding of Science Program, 1978 (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Purchase Possibilities (Demo), 1994 (Box 82, Folder 7)
    - Deborah Roudebush, 2002-2003 (Box 82, Folder 8)
    - Schedules (Teaching), 1993-2004 (Box 82, Folder 9)
    - Science Education Materials, 1993-1994, undated (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - Science Fair Talk, 1983-1986 (Box 82, Folder 11)
    - Scoville Visiting Lectureship Program, 1987-1989 (Box 82, Folder 12)
    - Sigma Xi Certificate, 1993 (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Skyline Correspondence, etc., 1985-1989 (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - Skyline Scripts, 1985-1987 (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Skyline Scripts, 1988-1990 (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - Jon Staib Celebration, 2007 (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Student Advising, 1993-1995 (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - Student Roast, 1995 (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - Summer Institute in Astronomy and Geology for Science Teachers, 1989 (Box 83, Folder 8)
    - Summer Study, 1996-1998 (Box 83, Folder 9)
    - Supplementary Grant for Faculty Research, 1979-1981 (Box 83, Folder 10)
    - Jerry Taylor Retirement, 2004 (Box 83, Folder 11)
    - Teaching Award, 1999-2001 (Box 83, Folder 12)
    - "Thinkings a Fundamental Ability," Notes for Executive Seminar, 1980 (Box 83, Folder 13)
    - UMSC 100: Academic Aspects, 1994 (Box 83, Folder 14)
    - UMSC 102 A & B: Academics & Sequencing, 1994 (Box 83, Folder 15)
    - UMSC Committee, 1993-1994 (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - UMSC Testing Assessment, 1994 (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - United Campuses to Prevent Nuclear War (UCAM) presentation, 1987-1988 (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Y-Quest Proposal, 1993 (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Highschool Physics Teachers Meeting, 1986-1989 (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Washington & Lee job opening, 2003 (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - Visiting Scholars Program, 1996-1999 (Box 84, Folder 7)
    - Visiting Scholars Program: Thomas Eisner, 1987-1988 (Box 84, Folder 8)
    - Visiting Scholars Program: Norman Herz & Francisco Ayala, 1993-1994 (Box 84, Folder 9)
    - Visiting Scholars Program: Claire Parkinson, 2002-2005 (Box 84, Folder 10)
    - Visiting Scholar Nomination, Claire Parkinson, 2003 (Box 84, Folder 11)
    - Steven Whisnant Recommendation, 2005-2008 (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Weekly & Daily Schedules Meeting Minutes and Notes (Folder 1 of 3), 1988-1991, undated (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - Weekly & Daily Schedules Meeting Minutes and Notes (Folder 2 of 3), 1988-1991, undated (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Weekly & Daily Schedules Meeting Minutes and Notes (Folder 3 of 3), 1988-1991, undated (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Weekly & Monthly Schedules, 2000-2011 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Weekly Calendars and Miscellaneous Articles, 1970-2006 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Yearly Calendars, 2008-2011 (Box 85, Folder 7)
  - 4.3: Canadian Faculty Residency, 2000-2005
    - Acadia Institute for Teaching and Technology (AITT), Physics at Acadia, 2001-2004 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Acadia University Certificates, Microsoft Office, 2004 (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Acadia University general materials, 2003-2004 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Acadia University Journals, 2004 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Acadia University Prep, 2004 (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Acadia University Published Materials, 2002-2004 (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - Assorted Canadian Newspapers, 2004 (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - Business Cards & Contacts, Various media, 2002-2004 (Box 86, Folder 8)
    - Canadian Maps, Brochures, & travel guides, 2004 (Box 86, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, Canada Faculty Residency, 2004 (Box 86, Folder 10)
    - Dalhousie University 2004/2005 Calendar, 2004 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Dalhousie University Site Visit, 2003-2004 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Faculty in residence handwritten notes, calendars, 2004 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Fulbright Scholar Program Application, 2002-2003 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Bryan Latta Correspondence, Acadia University Visit, 2003 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Maritime Universities site visits, 2002-2004 (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Physics 4513, Acadia University, 2004 (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Phys 4513 x1, Special Topics in Physics: Astrophysics, Acadia University, 2004 (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Physics and Beyond: A Semester in the Canadian Maritimes, 2004 (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - Physics Departments in Canada, 2003-2005 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Physics in Canada, 2000-2001 (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Return trip from Canada to US, Receipt & correspondence, 2004 (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - St. Francis Xavier University Site Visit, 2004 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - St. Mary's University Material & notes, 2002-2004 (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - St. Mary's University Published Materials, 2003-2005 (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - St. Mary's University site visit, 2004 (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - Summary Presentation of Canada faculty residency, 2004-2005 (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - University of New Brunswick site visit, 2004 (Box 88, Folder 9)
    - University of Prince Edward Island, Physics Department Assessment, 2001 (Box 88, Folder 10)
- Series 5: Professional Development and Activities, 1958-2011
  Arranged alphabetically by organization (where applicable) and then chronologically.
  This series consists of materials related to Dr. Ingham's involvement in professional organizations other than JMU or the physics department. This includes scholarly conferences and workshops that he attended, lectures presented, certifications from non-JMU affiliated organizations, and copies of his resume. Organizations represented include the American Association of Physics Teachers (AAPT), the Chesapeake Section of the American Association of Physics Teachers (CSAAPT), the Virginia Academy of Science.
  - AAPT Meeting, 1982 (Box 88, Folder 11)
  - AAPT Summer Meeting, 1994 (Box 88, Folder 12)
  - AAPT Committee on the History and Philosophy of Physics, 1999-2000 (Box 88, Folder 13)
  - AAPT Committee on the History and Philosophy of Physics, 2000-2001 (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - AAPT Area Chairs Handbook, 2001 (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - AAPT Summer Meeting, 2001 (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - AAPT Summer Meeting, 2001 (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - AAPT Summer Meeting, 2001 (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - AAPT Summer Meeting, Introduction of Joe Eberly, 2001 (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - AAPT Summer Meeting, Tony French Introduction of Emil Wolf, 2001 (Box 89, Folder 7)
  - AAPT Summer Meeting, 2002 (Box 89, Folder 8)
  - AAPT/APA Topical Conference of Departmental Chairs, 1988 (Box 89, Folder 9)
  - AEL Conference, 1994-1995 (Box 89, Folder 10)
  - AIP/CHP Newsletter, 1986-1991 (Box 89, Folder 11)
  - AP Annual Conference, 2008 (Box 89, Folder 12)
  - Archipelago Course Development, 1998 (Box 89, Folder 13)
  - Business cards and notes, 1994-1995 (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Caltech News, 1997-2005 (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - Chautaugua, "How Life Began", 1979-1980 (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - Chautaugua, "How Life Began", 1998 (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - Chautaugua, University of Kentucky, 1999 (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - Chautaugua, 2005 (Box 90, Folder 6)
  - College Board/AP Physics Redesign, 1958 (Box 90, Folder 7)
  - College Board/AP Course Descriptions Physics B and Physics C, 1997-2001 (Box 90, Folder 8)
  - College Board/AP Course Descriptions Physics B and Physics C Released Exams, 1998 (Box 90, Folder 9)
  - College Board/AP Report to the Nation, 2006 (Box 90, Folder 10)
  - College Board/AP Annual Conference, 2007 (Box 90, Folder 11)
  - CS AAPT Meeting Materials, 1995-2001 (Box 90, Folder 12)
  - CS AAPT Nominating Committee, 1997-2002 (Box 90, Folder 13)
  - CS AAPT Springs Paper, 1997-2000 (Box 90, Folder 14)
  - CS AAPT Fall Meeting, 1998 (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - CS AAPT Correspondence Miscellaneous Meeting Materials, 1998-2002 (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - CS AAPT Spring Meeting, "Dopple Curves for Cruising Airplanes, 1999 (Box 91, Folder 3)
  - CS AAPT Fall Meeting, 1999 (Box 91, Folder 4)
  - CS AAPT Spring Meeting, 2000 (Box 91, Folder 5)
  - CS AAPT Fall Meeting, 2000 (Box 91, Folder 6)
  - CS AAPT Spring Meeting, 2001 (Box 91, Folder 7)
  - CS AAPT Fall Meeting, Foucault Pendulum, 2001 (Box 91, Folder 8)
  - CS AAPT Fall Meeting, 2002 (Box 91, Folder 9)
  - CS AAPT Fall Meeting, 2003 (Box 91, Folder 10)
  - CS AAPT Spring Meeting, "Science and Technology in James Madison's World", 2004 (Box 91, Folder 11)
  - CS AAPT Fall Meeting, 2008 (Box 91, Folder 12)
  - CSUMS Application, 2006 (Box 91, Folder 13)
  - Digital Photography & Video All-Day Workshop, 2011 (Box 91, Folder 14)
  - DSMC Conference, 2005 (Box 92, Folder 1)
  - Eisenhower Regional Math/Science Consortium, 1994-1995 (Box 92, Folder 2)
  - Journal of Chemical Education submission "E=MC2: An Intuitive Derivation", 2007 (Box 92, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous professional activities materials, 1988-2008 (Box 92, Folder 4)
  - MIT Alumni, 2003-2007 (Box 92, Folder 5)
  - National Academy of Sciences/National Research Council Presentation, 1999-2000 (Box 92, Folder 6)
  - NCUR Conference, 1996 (Box 92, Folder 7)
  - NSF Chautaugua Program, 1999 (Box 92, Folder 8)
  - NSF S-STEM, 2008 (Box 92, Folder 9)
  - NSRC Conference, 1993-1994 (Box 92, Folder 10)
  - Nuclear Security Workshops, 1986-1988 (Box 92, Folder 11)
  - Nuclear War Education Conference, George Mason University, 1986 (Box 92, Folder 12)
  - PKAL Summer Institute, 2002 (Box 92, Folder 13)
  - Professional Development Possibilities, 1996-1999 (Box 92, Folder 14)
  - Project SCIENCE, Dabney S. Lancaster Community College, 1992-1994 (Box 92, Folder 15)
  - PhysTEC, 2005 (Box 92, Folder 16)
  - PhysTEC and PTRA, 2001 (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - Résumés, 1982-1992 (Box 93, Folder 2)
  - Résumés, 1994-2003 (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - Sigma Xi Annual Meeting and International Forum, 1991 (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - Sigma Xi Annual Meeting, 1993 (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - Sigma Xi Full Membership, 1987-1990 (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Special Relativity, 1992 (Box 93, Folder 7)
  - SPIN-UP, 2001-2002 (Box 93, Folder 8)
  - SPIN-UP SUNY Geneseo Site Visit, 2001-2002 (Box 93, Folder 9)
  - Towson Physics Department Review, 2002-2003 (Box 93, Folder 10)
  - Travel, 1977-1982 (Box 93, Folder 11)
  - United States Association for Young Physicists Tournaments, 2008-2009 (Box 93, Folder 12)
  - University of Maryland Physics Education Articles, 1994-2000 (Box 93, Folder 13)
  - Using Confer on the Rocky Mountain Exchange, 1993 (Box 93, Folder 14)
  - Virginia Academy of Science, 1977-1995 (Box 93, Folder 15)
  - Virginia Academy of Science, 1986 (Box 93, Folder 16)
  - Virginia Academy of Science Talk, 1978 (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Virginia Task Force on Physics, 1995-1996 (Box 94, Folder 2)
- Series 6: Physics Miscellaneous, 1970-2005
  This series contains material related to Dr. Ingham and physics, but does not necessarily fit within any of the other series. Included in this series are quotes, and comics, and personal correspondence.
  - Apt Quotes (Patterson), undated (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - Artwork, 1988-1992 (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - B:quote 1.doc, undated (Box 94, Folder 5)
  - B:quote 2.doc, undated (Box 94, Folder 6)
  - B:quote 3.doc, 1982 (Box 94, Folder 7)
  - B:quote 4.doc, 1981 (Box 94, Folder 8)
  - B:quote 5.doc, 1982 (Box 94, Folder 9)
  - B:quote 6.doc, undated (Box 94, Folder 10)
  - B:quote 7.doc, undated (Box 94, Folder 11)
  - David Carter Essay, 1990 (Box 94, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, 1977-1986 (Box 94, Folder 13)
  - Comics & stories, 1974-1976 (Box 94, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1991-1995 (Box 94, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 2002-2005 (Box 94, Folder 16)
  - East Stroudsburg State & Madison Correspondence, 1971-1993 (Box 94, Folder 17)
  - "I Understand the Physics, but I Just Can't Do The Problems", undated (Box 94, Folder 18)
  - Levity, 2005 (Box 94, Folder 19)
  - Philip Morrison Correspondence, 2003 (Box 94, Folder 20)
  - Philip Morrison Memorial, 2004-2005 (Box 94, Folder 21)
  - Music: Articles & Photos, 1977-1985 (Box 94, Folder 22)
  - MUSIC: Record Inventory & Want List, 1980-1983 (Box 94, Folder 23)
  - Off-Campus Correspondence, 1970-1989 (Box 94, Folder 24)
  - Office of the Governor News Release, 1998 (Box 94, Folder 25)
  - Poetry and the Sky, undated (Box 94, Folder 26)
  - Quotation Index, undated (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - Quotes, 1984-1998 (Box 95, Folder 2)
  - Quotes, undated (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - Quotes, Parables, & Rallying Cries, 1992-1997 (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - Quotes to be entered, undated (Box 95, Folder 5)
  - Robert Road Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - Scraps & Ideas, 1989-1997 (Box 95, Folder 7)
  - Vardaman Smith Correspondence, 2002 (Box 95, Folder 8)
  - Song Lyrics, 2009-2010 (Box 95, Folder 9)
  - Song Lyrics, undated (Box 95, Folder 10)
  - Whimsey, 1992 (Box 95, Folder 11)
  - XQ File, 1992 (Box 95, Folder 12)
- Series 7: Chronological Files, 1986-2013
  Arranged chronologically.